<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cats &#8211; Anna Stantchevas Cat Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/cats/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 15:36:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cropped-cropped-European-Shorthair-Cat-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Cats &#8211; Anna Stantchevas Cat Blog</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">200508835</site>	<item>
		<title>Balinese-Javanese Cat Breed</title>
		<link>/balinese-javanese-cat-breed/</link>
					<comments>/balinese-javanese-cat-breed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anna]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 15:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=35</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The slender yet muscular Javanese cat is often said to resemble a ballerina – it certainly has all the grace and charm. Intelligent and active, Javanese cats are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>The slender yet muscular Javanese cat is often said to resemble a ballerina – it certainly has all the grace and charm. Intelligent and active, Javanese cats are loyal, chatty felines who make great companions and are ideal for households with children and other cat-friendly pets. </em></p>



<h2>Appearance</h2>



<p>Just about everything about this breed can be described as long; long tail, long legs, and a long&nbsp;yet muscular body. The tail is slender and tapers towards the tips.&nbsp;The legs, which are slightly longer at the back, end in small round paws. The Javanese has a semi-long coat with hair that is as fine and thin as silk. Hair on the tail is a little longer than the rest of the body and forms a plume.</p>



<p>The eyes are beautifully almond shaped and come in radiant green for solid colors and all over patterns, or a hauntingly dark blue for pointed cats. While the triangular shaped head is considered medium sized on such a long gives it the illusion of being quite small. A long nose, fine muzzle, and slightly pointed ears which start from a wide base finish off the look of intelligence and fine breeding for this svelte breed.</p>



<h2>History</h2>



<p>The Javanese cat came about during a controlled Balinese breeding program during the 1950s – these long-haired Siamese cats were named after the graceful Balinese dancers. Later, breeders introduced ColourPoint Shorthairs to the program, which produced cats with stunning coat colours. Due to their closeness to the Balinese breed, they were named for the closest island to Bali –&nbsp;which is the island of Java, renowned&nbsp;for its coffee bean production.</p>



<h2>Javanese Cat Personality</h2>



<p>The Javanese is as intelligent as it looks and like their Siamese cousins, are quite vocal. They are a sociable breed and make great pets for homes with children and get on well with other household pets. They also love to be ‘helpful’ around the house, and will happily follow you around the house from room to room, often getting under your feet.</p>



<p>Javanese cats are athletic, agile and they love to play – they are quick to learn tricks and enjoy a game of&nbsp;fetch. When you’re home&nbsp;make sure they receive&nbsp;lots of attention, as they are prone to mischief or depression if left to their own devices for extended&nbsp;periods of time.</p>



<p>Javanese are also excellent mousers so any furry little critters who dare step over the threshold of your home will find their days numbered.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/balinese-javanese-cat-breed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">35</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Abyssinian Cat</title>
		<link>/abyssinian-cat/</link>
					<comments>/abyssinian-cat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anna]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 15:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is an Uncommon Kitty! Your best kitty friend senses your moods, is curious about your day, and has purred her way into your heart. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h1>This is an Uncommon Kitty!</h1>



<p>Your best kitty friend senses your moods, is curious about your day, and has purred her way into your heart. Chances are that you chose her because you like Abyssinians (sometimes called “Abys”) and you expected her to have certain traits that would fit your lifestyle, like:</p>



<ul><li>Alert, curious, and busy</li><li>Has a quiet or soft voice</li><li>Loves jumping and being in high places</li><li>Entertaining &#8211; likes to &#8220;perform&#8221; for her owners</li><li>Graceful, quick, and agile</li><li>Highly interactive and playful with owners</li></ul>



<p>But here are some other traits to consider:</p>



<ul><li>May want to constantly be involved in your activities</li><li>People-oriented and should not be left alone for long periods of time</li><li>Fearless and can get into trouble if not properly supervised</li><li>Has a tendency to escape, wander, and roam</li><li>May not do well in small confined spaces like apartments; lots of room to roam is ideal</li><li>Can have an unstable temperament if not bred properly, including nervousness, shyness, or fearfulness</li></ul>



<p>Overall, she&#8217;s full of personality, and you love her for it! She is an inquisitive and outgoing little busybody. Include her in your daily activities and she will be a playful and affectionate companion.</p>



<p>The Abyssinian is thought to have originated in Southeast Asia and the Indian Coast. They are said to be one of the oldest cat breeds, resembling cats depicted in Egyptian tombs. Abys have a distinctive wildcat look with their ticked coat and large erect ears. They are a highly social breed and can be demanding of attention. They do well in multi-cat households due to their social nature. Not a snuggly lap cat, Abyssinians are in constant motion, either exploring or playing. They are fond of water and are even known to play fetch. The Abyssinian is people-oriented and can be demanding of your attention.</p>



<h2>Your Abyssinian&#8217;s Health</h2>



<p>We know that because you care so much about your cat, you want to take great care of her. That is why we have summarized the health concerns we will be discussing with you over the life of your Aby. By knowing about the health concerns common among Abyssinians, we can help you tailor an individual preventive health plan and hopefully prevent some predictable risks in your pet.</p>



<p>Many diseases and health conditions are genetic, meaning they are related to your pet’s breed. The conditions we will describe here have a significant rate of incidence or a strong impact upon this breed particularly, according to a general consensus among feline genetic researchers and veterinary practitioners. This does not mean your cat will have these problems, only that she may be more at risk than other cats. We will describe the most common issues seen in Abyssinians to give you an idea of what may come up in her future. Of course, we can’t cover every possibility here, so always check with us if you notice any unusual signs or symptoms.</p>



<p>This guide contains general health information important to all felines as well as information on genetic predispositions for Abyssinians. The information here can help you and your pet’s healthcare team plan for your pet’s unique medical needs together. At the end of the article, we have also included a description of what you can do at home to keep your Aby looking and feeling her best. We hope this information will help you know what to watch for, and we will all feel better knowing that we’re taking the best possible care of your friend.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/abyssinian-cat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">30</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>American Bobtail Cat</title>
		<link>/american-bobtail-cat/</link>
					<comments>/american-bobtail-cat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anna]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 15:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=26</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Characteristics of American Bobtail Cats If you like the idea of having an unusual cat with an exotic look and substantial size, American Bobtails may [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Characteristics of American Bobtail Cats</h2>



<p>If you like the idea of having an unusual cat with an exotic look and substantial size, American Bobtails may be just the breed for you. Learn more about the characteristics and temperament of these sweet kitties.</p>



<h2>Physical Characteristics of American Bobtail Cats</h2>



<p>American Bobtails look very much like a Bobcat. This cat&#8217;s exotic, wild look comes from the combination of its size, coloring and lack of a tail.</p>



<p>This domestic cat is a large cat. The body is well muscled and powerful. The males can weigh in excess of 14 pounds, although the females are somewhat smaller.</p>



<p>The tail, or lack of it, is the piece de resistance for most people. The short tail should be no longer than the hock and will be visible above the back of the animal. It will stand up nearly straight, showing only a slight curve. The lack of a tail is genetic with these cats; it is a characteristic that most cats in the breed share. The short tail can be anywhere from one to four inches. This is only an average, and the tails can be shorter or longer.</p>



<p>The short tail gene of the American Bobtail is dominant. This means that the cat has to be short-tailed to produce bob-tailed offspring. It is possible for a fully-tailed kitten to be born in a litter of Bobtail kittens.</p>



<p>The coat is thick and luxurious with two types of fur. The first layer, nearest the skin, is similar to any short-haired cat. The outer layer is made up of medium length hair that is resistant to water. The coat can come in almost any color or pattern. The ears may be tipped with long hair much like a wild Bobcat.</p>



<p>American Bobtails are a slow-maturing breed of cat and may take as long as three years to completely mature.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/american-bobtail-cat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>European shorthair</title>
		<link>/european-shorthair/</link>
					<comments>/european-shorthair/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anna]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 15:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=23</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a European shorthair cat. The European Shorthair, called the European in FIFe and WCF is a cat breed originating in Sweden.[4] The term has also been used as an elaborate [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This is a European shorthair cat.</p>



<p>The <strong>European Shorthair</strong>, called the <strong>European</strong> in FIFe and WCF is a cat breed originating in Sweden.<sup>[4]</sup> The term has also been used as an elaborate way of referring to common domestic cats of Europe, causing some confusion as the pedigree cats of this breed also should resemble the typical domestic cats of Europe. In WCF a similar breed is known as <strong>Celtic Shorthair</strong> and was at a time considered the same breed, but this breed has some difference from the Europeans, and the WCF now register true Europeans under this breed name instead of under Celtic Shorthair.</p>



<h2>Health and welfare issues</h2>



<p>European Shorthairs are generally a robust breed without too many problems. Because they have been bred with Persians in the past there is small chance of a being affected by polycystic kidney disease. This disease causes kidney problems because of the cysts or fluid filled holes which develop progressively. There is a gene test available so it is definitely worth asking the breeders about the status of their cats – good breeders should know about it.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/european-shorthair/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">23</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
